《狂蟒之灾2：搜寻血兰》
(纽约市)
你根本就是唬我们
You've sold us a bill of goods, Gordon.
你承诺过会研发出 能对抗各种疾病的新药
Promised new drugs to fight everything from the common cold to cancer.
- 我们会实现承诺的 - 对不起 探险结束了
- We'll deliver everything we promised. - I'm sorry,but the adventure is over.
我们决定执行...
We're exercising our option to liquidate...
拜伦米契生技公司的买卖权
...Byron & Mitchell Research Limited.
杰克 让这些人看看 我们能让他们赚多少钱
Jack,show these people how filthy rich we're gonna make them,please.
我想你不明白我在说什么
I don't think you understand what I just said.
我想我明白
Oh,I think I understand.
杰克
Jack.
不朽之花
Perrinia immortalis.
血兰花
The Blood Orchid.
霍顿于1892年首度发现
First described in 1892 by Houghton...
他也是我们从婆罗洲取回样本前 最后一位目赌它的人
...the last person to see it until our team brought a sample from Borneo.
它休眠期七年 开花期只有半年
It lies dormant for seven years, then blooms for just six months.
各位 这表示我们太走运了
Which means we just got lucky as hell,gentlemen.
听过"海夫利克极限"吗?
Anyone here familiar with the Hayflick limit?
海夫利克提出细胞在死亡前
He proposed a cell could only replicate 56 times...
只能复制56次
...before it died from a buildup of toxins.
他相信这就是人类死亡的原因
According to him, it's the reason we die.
要是能超越这个极限呢?
But what if we could transcend that limit?
那是不可能的
That would be impossible.
我们的资料可不是这么说的
Not according to our data.
根据我们的研究显示 不朽之花中的一种化学成份
Our research indicates the presence of a chemical in Perrinia immortalis...
可以延长细胞的寿命
...that can significantly prolong cellular life.
我无法同意这点
I can't support this.
那跟我想的一样吗?
Does that mean what I think it means?
这算是医药界的
Are we talking about a pharmaceutical equivalent...
不老泉?
...to the fountain of youth?
没错
Exactly.
那一定比威而钢还赚
That'd be bigger than Viagra.
- 你们做过人体实验了? - 还没办法做
- Have you put this into human trials? - We can't yet.
样本在初次研究后已经腐败
Our sample was degraded in the initial study.
我们需要更多的血兰花
We need more of the orchid.
那是唯一的问题
See,and that's our only problem, gentlemen.
那种兰花只剩两周的开花期
That orchid is only in bloom for another two weeks.
那你们还等什么?
Well,what the hell are you waiting for?
快滚去婆罗洲啊
Get your asses down to Borneo.
好耶
Yes.
(婆罗洲 帕兰省)
- 欢迎莅临婆罗洲 - 谢了
- Welcome to Borneo. - Thanks.
- 这幅景象有什么问题? - 我不知道 你在里面?
- What's wrong with this picture? - I don't know. Let me see,you're in it?
我们无船可用
We don't have a boat,okay?
你的公司只负责这件事:租船
Your company had one responsibility: get a boat.
- 你却搞砸了 - 是你们的小姐负责租船 不是我们
- And you've already screwed it up. - Wait. Your girl chartered the boat.
珊昨晚跟船公司确认 款项没付
Sam confirmed with the company. They're waiting for your payment.
我有消息
Hey. Hey,I've got something.
款项已经付清了
Payment cleared.
真的啊?
Really?
- 那船呢? - 船不会来了
- Where's the boat? - It's not coming.
所有船公司都暂停营运
All of the charter companies have shut down.
雨季期间没人愿意冒险去上游
No one'll risk going upriver till after the rainy season.
- 那要等多久? - 二到三周
- And when's that? - Two,three weeks.
那种兰花最多只能再开一周
The orchid's only in bloom for one more week,tops.
有个本地船长叫金宋
There's a local captain named Jin-Soon.
听说他愿意带任何人去上游 只要价钱对
I'm told he'll take anyone upriver, for the right price.
你确定是这里?
Are you sure this is the place?
他们说是红色大门这家
They said the one with the red door.
里面一定有人在玩俄罗斯轮盘
I bet you somebody's playing Russian roulette in there.
也许你玩的时候 我们会走运
Maybe we'll get lucky and you'll get a turn.
你们两个去开房间算了 走吧
Hey,why don't you two just get a room. Come on,Sam.
在这等着
Wait here.
好啊 随便你
Yeah,if you insist.
嘿!嘿!
Hey! Hey!
金宋
Jin-Soon.
金宋?
Jin-Soon?
你的印尼文真烂
Your lndonesian sucks.
- 说英文吧 - 听说你能带我们去上游
- Stick to English. - We heard you could take us upriver.
在雨季?
In rainy season?
那可不便宜
Won't be cheap.
我们付你两万五
We can pay you 25,000.
- 我跟船长谈谈 - 你不是船长?
- I'll have a talk with the captain. - You're not the captain?
金宋!
Jin-Soon!
这些观光客要找船 我说了雨季不行
These tourists need a boat. I told them not in the rainy season.
- 你就是金宋? - 本地人取的绰号
- You're Jin-Soon? - Local nickname.
我叫强森 比尔强森
Name's Johnson. Bill Johnson.
印尼人发音不好
It's a pronunciation thing.
你们可以用两万五租我的船
And you can rent my boat for 25 grand.
但是要我开它
Now,you want me to drive it, well...
就得加码到五万
...that'll cost you 50.
五万? 你喝到茫啦?
Fifty grand? Are you high?
你不用回答这个问题
You know what? Don't answer that.
我不信任他
I'm not trusting him with the expedition.
听着 小姐 我们少废话
Listen. Lady. Let's cut the bullshit,please.
要是有船公司肯载你们
If one of the other charter companies could take you...
你们现在早在河上了
...you'd be on the river by now.
你们是因为束手无策才来找我
You only came to me because you're desperate.
我的价钱就是五万
Fifty grand's my price.
不接受
Take it...
就免谈
...or leave it.
那比捡破烂的铁皮屋还恐怖
I've seen subway cars in better shape than this.
它也许不中看
Yeah,she may be ugly...
但是它很给力
...but she puts out.
- 妈的! - 你怎么拖这么久?
- Shit! - What took you so long?
全球定位仪 卫星导航系统...
Hey,you try getting a GPS locator, a Sat-Nav EchoStar...
这些仪器很难通过印尼海关的
...and a UV spectrometer past lndonesian customs.
- 开始抱怨了 - 没错
- Complaining already. - Yeah.
- 你宁愿待办公室? - 废话
- You rather be back in the office? - Hell,yeah.
我有周六篮球决赛贵宾券
I had courtside seats at the Garden on Saturday.
我原本会坐在名人之间看球
I was gonna sit right between Spike and Woody.
妈呀 不会坐那个吧?
Oh,man,is that our ride?!
乐观点 至少天气不错
Look at the bright side,Cole. At least the weather's nice.
队医班道格 你一定是珊了
Ben Douglas,team doctor. You must be Sam.
对 我们通过电话
Yeah. We spoke on the phone.
很高兴你能加入
Glad to have you aboard.
我会让你付出代价的
I'm gonna get you for this.
好耶 这下好玩了
Oh,yeah. This could be fun.
别妄想了 老兄
You can forget about that,dog.
你搞不定那个妞的
That's one car you ain't never gonna catch.
总是有办法的
There's always a way.
- 你的成员有点欠缺经验吧? - 我带过的研究生
- Your team's a little green,huh? - My former grad students.
都是顶尖的
Best in their field.
贵公司创办人的名言
Here's a tip for Wexell-Hall:
想要拥有青年才俊
You want the best young talent...
就要趁早招募
...recruit early.
是啊 我相信珊一定很有一套
Yes,I'm sure Sam's very talented.
我讨厌她的态度
I think I resent that.
你和另一位小姐可以睡这里
You and the other gal can stay in here.
你住在这里
You live here.
你的语气听起来很感动
The way you say that, I can tell you're impressed.
好了
All right.
要是你有任何需要...
If you need anything....
嗯...
Well...
要是有需要 那你就惨了
...if you need anything, you're shit out of luck.
(血腥玛丽号)
行了
Okay.
探险队就是在这里发现兰花的
Now,this is where the exploratory team found the orchid.
萨坦盆地
In the Selatan Basin.
- 他们花了3天时间 - 是啊
- It took them three days to get upriver. - Yeah.
那是在雨季之前
That was before the rainy season.
现在有些水道可能很危险
These waterways could be dangerous now.
- 你说过能把我们安全送到的 - 没错
- You said you'd get us there safely. - And I will.
但安全并不代表快速
But safe isn't always quick.
我们沿着河道慢慢开
We'll work our way up one bend at a time.
如果苗头不对 就改变航道
If I don't like what I see, we change course.
不能一开始就找最快的航道
Can't chart the fastest route before you begin.
已经找好了
Already have.
大家看看吧?
Check it. All right.
我们连结了太空总署和亚洲卫星
Now,we're uplinked in real time to NASA and AsiaSatCom.
在最佳状况下
Now,under ideal conditions...
这是最快的航道
...this is the fastest route.
但加上过去十年的天气模式后
But once we superimpose weather patterns for the past 10 years...
然后再加以推测
...and then extrapolate....
好了 到萨坦盆地的最佳航道
Bingo! It's Padrang to the Selatan Basin.
我太行了
I'm a bad man.
我们只剩不到一礼拜能采集兰花
We got less than a week to get to that orchid.
要是你无法达成任务 把钱还来
If you can't get the job done, give our money back...
- 我们找别人 - 我会把你们送到的
- ...and we'll get somebody who can. - I'll get you there.
老天爷
God help me.
有东西攻击我 里面有东西
Something attacked me!
- 哦!好可怕! - 她说有东西攻击她
- Oh,my God! - She said something attacked her.
别...别进去
No,no,no!
没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
你搞什么?你吓坏它了
What the helI'd you do? You scared him.
我吓坏它?
I scared him?!
这是小刚
This is Kong.
小刚住这
Kong lives here.
你们是客人
You're guests.
亲切一点嘛
Be nice.
恶心的动物
Disgusting animal.
你现在没事了吧?
You okay now?
我没事 你别乱碰我
I'm fine. Just keep your hands off of me.
那可能有点难 但我会尽量设法
Oh,yeah. Well,it's gonna be tough, but I'll try.
不 那份报告在本周内要提交
No,no,the S-1 has to be on file before the week is out.
- 那正是重点 - 哈啰?
- That's the whole point. - Hello?
- S1一定要在本周内提交 - 没错
- The S-1 needs to be on file before.... - Yes,we were able to get on the river.
我们需要证管会的意见
That's the purpose. We need the comments from the SEC.
- 抱歉 - 我只能在这里收到讯号
- Excuse me. - It's the only place I can get reception.
- 快点搞定 我们要尽快准备好 - 不 那不可能...
- No,just get it done. Be ready to go.... - No,that's impossible....
- 喂?该死! - 哈啰?巴伯?可恶!
- Hello? Hello? Damn! - Hello? Bob? Damn it!
试试我的手机吧
Try my phone.
一样好用 而且还免钱
Works just as good, but it's free.
也许你可以用我的特制天线 增强你的收讯能力
Okay. Maybe you can use my special antenna to boost your reception.
青苔会阻碍我们攀爬 我们要找光滑的岩石表面
We're dealing with a lithophytic vine, so we want to search any rock face.
这崚线看来值得一试
Now,this ridge here seems a good bet.
珊
Sam.
好嘛 你觉得咧?
Come on,Sam. What do you say?
我们年轻 单身 又在婆罗洲
We're young. We're single. We're in Borneo.
你有什么好损失的?
What do you got to lose?
不满意可以转身就走 不用承诺
Not satisfied,walk away. No commitments.
不用承诺
"No commitments."
你还真大方
That's your pitch?
我有说不用承诺吗? 我是要你嫁给我
Did I say "No commitments"? I meant marry me.
接下来两周我都得面对他吗?
Am I gonna be dealing with this for the next two weeks?
没错
Yep.
你以前是杰克的学生?
So you were one of Jack's students?
对 他教我们植物药物学
Yeah. He was teaching a seminar on botanical pharmacology.
我一完成论文 他就雇用了我
Soon as I finished my dissertation, he hired me.
你还真有一手
Well,that's one way to get a leg-up.
这话什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
我刚毕业时也曾有教授要用我
I had a professor who wanted to hire me.
他要我做他的秘书
Of course,he wanted me to be his secretary.
我是不是哪里得罪你啦?
Look,if I've done something to offend you...
不 没有
No. No,dear,not at all.
事实上 我很羡慕你 我花了十年才有今日
Actually,I admire you. Took me 10 years to get where I am.
显然你们这代找到了捷径
Clearly,your generation has it figured out.
真好吃 你在哪学会煮这些菜的
Man,this is good. Where'd you learn to cook like this?
- 这是我在斯里兰卡学会的 - 你在那里干嘛?
- Little recipe I picked up in Sri Lanka. - What were you doing there?
无国界医生组织
Doctors Without Borders.
那是我平常的工作
It's my day job.
你们预期会需要医生?
You guys expect to need a doctor?
保险公司要求要有医生随行
Can't get the expedition bonded without one.
你们把我当迷人的保险条约就是啦
Well,you just think of me as a charming insurance policy.
嘿!
Hey!
你吃过晚餐了
You've had your dinner.
走开
Get out of here.
我是怎么说的?
What'd I say?
没有太多的...
There's not that much....
我才不要睡上面 我也不要睡地板
I'm not sleeping up there. I ain't sleeping on the floor.
我不要睡在那个烂...
I ain't sleeping on no damn....
- 妈的 那是什么? - 那是什么玩意?
- Oh,shit. What was that? - What the hell was that?
- 有东西被吃了 - 被什么吃了?
- Something's getting eaten. - By what?
这是丛林
Everything gets eaten out here.
万物都会被猎食
It's the jungle.
小刚
Kong.
你们有看见小刚吗?
Hey. You guys seen Kong?
昨晚之后就没见过
No. Not since last night.
你跑去哪了?
Where are you?
小刚?
Kong?
如果要食品药物管理局同意 我们下个月就需要结果
We need those results by next month if we want the FDA off our backs.
喂?该死!
Hello? Shit!
我听不见你
I can't hear you!
你听得见我吗?
Can you hear me now?
现在呢?
How about now?
你现在听得见吗?
Can you hear me now?
- 你现在听得见吗? - 我们都听见了
- Can you hear me now? - We can!
你现在听得见吗?
Can you hear me now?
- 葛儿 我的老天 - 该死
- Gail! Oh,my God. - Shit.
快停船!
Stop the boat!
- 我去救她 - 好的
- I'll go. - All right.
葛儿 你听得见我吗?
Hey,Gail! Can you hear me now?!
我要宰了你
Oh,I'm gonna kill you!
游过来 快 快点 游过来
Stroke,Gail,stroke. Come on.
- 小心背后 - 葛儿 水温还好吧?
- Watch your back. - Hey,Gail! How's the water?
把电话扔了 它会妨碍你游泳
Drop the phone. It's probably holding you back.
- 好了 抓住 - 冷静点
- All right. - Stay calm.
- 冷静点 - 把电话当救生浮筒用吧
- Stay calm. - Use your phone for flotation.
加油
All right,come on,Gail.
- 你就快到了 - 把杆子当电话握就行了
- You're almost there. - It's just like a phone.
我抓住了
I got it.
- 妈呀! - 该死!
- Holy shit! - Holy shit!
快上来
Come on! Come on!
- 快点! - 快啊!
- Get out! - Hurry up!
快点!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
- 快点! - 抓好!
- Come on! Come on! - Gail,grab it.
- 小心! - 小心!
- Look out! - Watch out!
哦 天啊!
Oh,my God.
刺它!刺它眼睛!
Get him,Bill! Get him,Bill! Get him in the eye,man!
比尔?
Bill?
他人呢?
Where'd he go?
- 他人呢? - 比尔!
- Where'd he go?! - Bill!
我没看到他
I don't see him.
- 他到哪去了? - 我的老天
- Where's he gone? - Oh,my God.
妈咧 你赢了
Oh,shit,you won.
- 你没事吧? - 我的电话掉了
- You're okay? - I lost my phone.
真是太遗憾了
Sorry to hear it.
这要不是我看过最勇敢的 就是最蠢的行径
That was either the bravest or the stupidest thing I've ever seen.
那没多大差别
It's a fine line.
- 没事了 - 谢谢
- Good as new. - Thanks.
敬葛儿
To Gail...
她明白与其被吃不如自己大吃
...who knows it's better to eat than be eaten.
- 敬葛儿 - 好耶 宝贝
- To Gail. - Yeah,yeah,baby.
为了找花儿差点被吃了
Almost eaten just to find a flower.
- 看起来还真不值得 - 这值得的
- Hardly seems worth it. - Oh,it's worth it.
你想想
I mean,think about it.
你以后每天都要服用的一颗药丸
A pill that you take every day for the rest of your life.
就算我们一颗最多只卖一元
Now,even if we charge, say,a dollar a pop...
- 我们就是亿万富翁了 - 我就说嘛
- ...we're billionaires. - Yeah.
- 我就说嘛 - 一瓶卖一百元
- That's what I'm talking about,baby. - At $100 a bottle...
连我都愿意去跟鳄鱼搏命
...I'll dive in that river and fight that croc myself.
要多少花才能拯救这世界?
So how many flowers does it take to save the world?
50朵花只能生产一盎司的药
Figure 50 orchids will yield about an ounce of chemical.
就算你有一整个球场的花
You could have a football field full of those orchids...
也还是没办法做人体实验
...still doesn't mean you can get it through human trials.
她根本就不相信你
She doesn't even believe in you.
干这行就是这样
Comes with the territory.
研究就是要冒点风险
In research, you've got to go out on a limb.
总是有人会怀疑你
And there's always someone waiting to chop it off.
你跑去哪了?
Where the hell have you been?
- 那东西真该死 - 你跑去哪了 小朋友?
- Damn that thing! - Where you been,boy?
冷静点
Calm down. Calm down.
- 真可怜 - 没事了 没事了
- Poor guy. - It's okay. It's all right.
它好像见了鬼似的
Looks like he's seen a ghost.
没事了 没事了 没事了
It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
万一葛儿说中了呢?
What if Gail's right?
在培养皿里做实验是一回事
I mean,cells in a petri dish are one thing.
- 人体实验又是另一回事 - 她错了
- Human trials are another. - She's wrong.
等不朽之花成品上市之后
And when it goes to product...
你我就能兑现手中的股票买卖权
...and you and I can cash in our stock options...
- 到时我们再让她好看 - 股票买卖权
- ...we'll rub her face in it. - Stock options.
我跟米契同意
I spoke to Mitchell.
各给你们0.5%
We're each giving you half a point.
我真不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
别说了
Don't say anything.
这是你应得的
You deserve it.
这一切
All this...
全都多亏了你
...wouldn't be possible without your work.
杰克
Jack.
我们说好不这样的
Thought we decided against that.
没错
Yeah. Yeah.
不过那应该也挺有趣的
You're right. It would be fun,though.
在河上游等着我们的
I mean,here we are, traveling upriver...
是我们此生最伟大的发现
...to the greatest discovery of our careers.
这兰花若真有效 到那时...
Now,if this orchid thing works out,then...
谁知道呢?
...who knows?
这就是我来的原因?
Is that why I'm here?
让你给我们再次发展的机会?
So you can give us one more try?
那是因为你是最顶尖的研究员
You're here because you're the best researcher I've got.
我打扰到你们了?
Am I interrupting something?
没...
No. No,I was....
- 我正打算上床睡觉 - 是啊
- I was just going to bed. - Yeah.
在那之前 我们得谈谈
Well,before you do that, we need to talk.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
看到水位没?
See the water level?
水位一高 曼河就很难航行
In high water, the Mendranang gets rough.
我们可以掉头回去找其他河道
We could turn around, try to find another course.
- 但那要多花两天时间 - 我们没那么多时间
- But that would take at least two days. - We don't have the time.
若这河无法通行 就要耗更久
If the river becomes impassable, it'll take a lot longer.
要是我们掉头回去 就完了
And if we turn back, then we're definitely screwed.
我们得冒险一试
We're gonna have to risk it.
要是我不想冒险呢?
What if I don't wanna risk it?
你知道这些花代表什么吗?
Do you have any idea what this flower means?
这是历史上最伟大的医药发现
We're talking about the biggest medical discovery in history.
听起来好像很厉害
That does sound great,Jack.
但我对历史一窍不通
But I was never any good at history.
你要我冒险强渡曼河
You want me to risk the Mendranang...
你就得多花五万元
...it'll cost you an extra 50 thousand.
成交
Done.
成交?
Done?
你不用去问那个女老板吗?
You gotta ask the boss lady or something?
我自掏腰包
I'll pay it myself.
好
All right.
就这么说定了
You got yourself a deal.
但如果有状况
But if we hit trouble...
你们就得听我的
...your people do what I say, you got that?
你是船长
You're the captain.
研究计划?
Research proposals?
对
Yeah. Research proposals.
你们不是我们唯一的对象
You're not the only company we're in bed with.
我们是最抢手 最顶尖的
We're the prettiest and most popular.
就像当红名模一样
Like sleeping with the head cheerleader.
不尽然
Not quite.
少来了 你爱死我们了
Come on,you know you love us.
我是爱你们的钱
I love your cash.
那你为什么不让我看档案?
Then let me get a look at that file.
等这个血兰花计划没了 你跟卫合创投就没戏唱了
After this orchid thing goes bust, you'll be finished at Wexell-Hall.
除非你还有别的案子
Unless you got something else lined up.
你真的很想看我们失败
You really wanna see us fail, don't you?
不想
No.
我只是认定你们会失败 我毕竟是科学家
I just think that you will. I am a scientist,you know.
科学家
Scientist.
那你在卫合创投做什么?
What're you doing at Wexell-Hall?
我喜欢科学
I like science.
只是我更喜欢钱
I just like money better.
我敬你
I'll drink to that.
河水泛滥 看不见河岸
River's flooded. We can't see the banks.
错过分叉点了?
Miss our turnoff?
就在前面
It's just ahead.
那是什么?
What the hell was that?
- 舵卡住了 - 什么?
- Rudder's jammed. - What?
小心
Watch out.
该死!
Shit!
大家快起来!
Get up! Everybody up!
嘿!
Hey.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
该死
Goddamn it.
引擎的衬片坏了
Shit! We've blown the head gasket.
我们没事吧?
Are we all right?
怎么回事啊?
Hey,what's going on?
- 怎么了? - 我们有麻烦了
- What is it? - We got problems.
- 怎么了? - 比尔 等等
- What's wrong,man? - Bill,wait.
你在扯什么?是什么问题?
What are you talking about? What problems?
该死 水流太强了
Son of a bitch. The current's too strong.
- 我们错过分叉点了 - 我知道 快啊
- We missed our turnoff. - I know. Come on,baby.
快啊
Come on,man.
- 什么? - 那是什么?
- What is it? - What is it?
你看到什么了?
What do you see?
快啊
Come on.
你行的 加油
You got this. Come on,girl.
- 大家抓紧了 - 抓什么?
- Everybody! Hang on! - Hang on to what?!
快啊!
Come on!
救命啊!
Oh,shit!
该死!
Holy shit.
船沉了!船沉了!
It's sinking,it's sinking!
- 克尔呢? - 游到岩石那里 往这边来
- Where's Cole? - Swim to the rocks,this way.
继续游
Keep going.
- 快 游到岩石那里 - 到岩石那里去
- Come on,get to the rocks. - Get to the rocks.
- 克尔呢?克尔! - 在那边!
- Where's Cole? Cole! - Over there.
在那边!继续游!把手给我!
Over there! Over there!
把手给我!
Come on,man. Give me your hand!
快点
Come on.
很好 珊 加油
You got it,Sam. Come on.
把手给我 我抓住你了
Give me your hand. I've got you,I've got you.
把手给我
Give me your hand, give me your hand.
好 我抓住你了
Okay,I got her.
你差点害死了我们 你差点害死了我们
You almost got us killed!
你以为我想吗?我的船没了
You think I wanted this? I just lost my damn boat!
你不救我们出去 钱也会没了
You'll lose your pay if you don't get us out.
早知有危险 你就该掉头回去
You said you'd get us there safely. You should've turned around.
够了!
That's enough!
现在吵这个一点用也没有
There's nothing we can do about that now.
只是浪费精力
It's a waste of energy.
我们还剩什么?
What have we got?
一些标本罐 地图... 一些水 没有食物
Some specimen jars, a map,a little water,no food.
硬碟挂了
Hard drive's ruined.
几乎所有装备都完了
Well,pretty much all the equipment's shot.
除了一具卫星电话 上网用的
Except one of the SAT phones still works. It's on-line.
感谢上天 我们可以找警察了
Thank God,we can call the police.
最近的巡逻队在帕兰
Police. The nearest river patrol is back in Padrang.
要找到我们就得越过那个
The only way to get to us is over that.
我们被困在这里了?
Are you saying we're stuck here?
也许没有
Maybe not.
我们在这 整个河谷都被淹没了
We're here. The valley's completely flooded.
但我有朋友在托库河开船
But I got a friend who operates a boat on the Tokut River.
我可以打电话找他 请他到纳加岩接我们
I can give him a call,and he can meet us here at Naga Rock.
那有多远?
How far is that?
我不知道 沿着河走一两天吧
I don't know. A two-day hike down the river.
但如果穿越丛林 可以减少一天的路程
But if we bushwhack, we cut at least a day off the trek.
你要走那里?
Oh,my God. You wanna go through that?
那是最短的路程
It's the shortest way.
傍晚就能平安到达托库河
We could be safely in the Tokut by nightfall.
那我们就能继续探险了
So we can continue with the expedition.
- 是啊 我会送你去找花 - 算了吧
- Yeah. I'll get you to the flower. - I don't care about that flower...
- 安全第一 - 那没有冲突
- ...just get us to safety. - It's the same thing.
我们可以在十小时内坐上船 或在这呆坐
We can either be on my buddy's boat in 10 hours,or we can sit here...
几天等巡逻队
...and wait for the river patrol for days.
你朋友 他靠得住吧?
Your friend. Is he reliable?
当然
Absolutely.
你最好别搞砸了
You better not screw me on this.
听起来你已经搞砸了
Sounds like you're already screwed,mate.
我付你两千元
Pay you two grand.
我需要你帮忙
I need you on this one,John.
是啊 看得出来
Yes,yes,so it seems.
听我说 我很想帮你 但我真的穷翻了
Look,Billy,I'd love to help you out, but I'm flat out,mate,you know.
也许你可以出五千?
Probably squeeze you in for, say,5 grand?
你开玩笑
You're killing me.
那是交情价
That's mates rates. Or you could always...
你想省钱可以自己走回去
...hike back to Padrang if you wanna save bucks.
- 就看你了 - 好吧 五千
- Up to you,pal. - Fine. Five.
- 帅啊! - 但你最好别失约
- Yes! - But you better be there.
不然我把你的丑事跟你老婆说
Otherwise,I'll tell your wife about that little trip to Bangkok.
老婆早跑啦
Wife's long gone,Billy.
早跑啦
Long gone,mate.
(李文斯顿私人财产)
各位 谈好了 准备上路
All right,people,we're on. Saddle up.
大家别走散了 这丛林很茂密 很容易迷路的
Stay together. This jungle is all green all the time,and you will get lost.
这活像在三温暖里踩登山机
It's like doing a StairMaster in a sauna.
是啊 我搞不好会中暑而死 但我铁定能练出紧翘的屁部
Yeah. I might die of a heat stroke, but I'll have a nice tight ass.
这就对了 克尔
That's the spirit,Cole.
- 要我帮你拿吗? - 这不是废话吗?
- You want me to grab that? - ls that a trick question?
拿去吧
Here,man.
坐在名人堆里看球...
Right between Spike and Woody.
你还好吧 珊?
You okay,Sam?
我很好
I'm fine.
危机让人能看清真正的男人
See,a crisis separates the real men from the pretenders.
是啊 我看得出来
Yeah. Can see that.
那个啊?
What,that?
那没什么
That's nothing.
我骗他帮我拿背包
I tricked him into taking my bag.
让我试试看吧?
Hey. Mind if I give it a try?
随你便
Knock yourself out.
嘿!
Hey.
很遗憾你的船没了
I'm sorry about your boat.
唉 真是...
Yeah,well...
反正它也挺烂的
...it was a piece of shit anyway.
能绕过去吗?
Can we go around?
可以 但那就得多浪费一天
Yeah,we could. But we'd lose another day.
我们走吧
Let's go.
妈啦
Shit.
别闹了
Hey. Knock it off.
- 妈啦 那是什么? - 什么是什么?
- Shit! What was that? - What was what?
- 有东西滑过去 - 拜托你别乱说
- Something just moved. - Please don't say that.
我是说真的 有东西滑过去
I'm serious. Something moved.
活的东西?
"Something just moved" as in something's alive?
是啊 又来了 这里面有东西
Shit! There it is again. There's something in here!
可能有上百万种生物吧
There's probably a million things in here.
他说的对 继续走吧
He's right. Just keep moving.
别闹了
Stop it.
我发誓 你再不停...
I swear to God,if you don't stop it....
很有趣
Very funny.
班?
Ben?
- 他人呢? - 该死!
- Where'd he go? - Shit!
救命!
Help me!
快跑!
Run!
- 那是什么鬼玩意? - 森蚺
- What the hell was that thing?! - Anaconda.
- 这下可好了! - 这里有那么大的蛇?
- Oh,great! - There's snakes out here that big?
- 对 不过... - 不过什么?它把他给吞了
- Yes,but... - But what? It swallowed him whole!
冷静下来听我说...
Calm down and listen for a second. I can explain...
你才冷静下来听我说 班被一条超级大蟒蛇给吞了!
No,you calm down and listen! Ben was eaten by a freaking snake.
- 超级大蟒蛇! - 克尔
- Okay? A freaking snake! - Cole.
- 老天!老天! - 克尔
- Oh,God. Oh,my God. I mean.... - Cole.
老天!老天! 你们有看到那玩意吗?
Oh,my God,did you see that thing?
我们根本打不赢它的
We don't got a chance against that!
我是说 米契 米契 你听我说
I mean,Mitchell. Mitchell. Listen to me,man.
拜托 我常看探索频道 我跟你说 我们毫无胜算
I watch the Discovery Channel. I'm telling you,we got no chance!
我们就像小老鼠一样 你们明白吗?
We're like mice in an aquarium. You understand?
我们死定了 我们死定了
I mean,we're gonna die,girl. We're gonna die!
克尔 冷静点
Cole,calm down. Okay?
- 好吗? - 好 杰克 我没事
- Okay? - All right,Jack,I'm okay.
我会乖乖
Okay. I'll just....
我会...
I'm gonna...
我会乖乖坐在这里 对不起
I'm gonna sit right here. I'm sorry. Sorry.
听着 南美大蟒蛇是有地盘的
Listen. Anacondas are territorial.
那种大小的蛇地盘一定很大
A snake that size will hunt a huge area.
几公里以内不会有其他的蛇
There won't be another one for miles.
我们得去坐船 那里没那么远
We gotta get to the boat. It's not that far.
只要我们一起继续前进
So if we keep moving and stick together...
- 就应该不会有事 - 应该不会?
- ...we should be fine. - We should be?!
它们会长多大?
How big do they get?
那是我看过最大条的了 变种怪物
That was the biggest one I've ever seen by far. A freak of nature.
再遇见另一条这么大的机率很低
The odds of running into another that size are astronomical.
吞了班的那条难道
Yeah,but how do we know the one that got Ben...
不会追我们?
...is not gonna come after us?
它们要花好几个星期消化
It takes them weeks to digest.
那么大块的肉 能让它安静好一阵子
Meal like that, he'll be sleeping it off for a while.
我们赶快去搭船回家吧
Let's just get to that boat and get home.
那血兰花呢?
What about the orchid?
你不会吧
You've gotta be kidding me.
它要再过七年才会再开花
It won't bloom for another seven years.
- 探险已经结束了 杰克 - 等一等
- This expedition is over,Jack. - Now,hold on a second,Gail.
- 这上面可投注了不少金钱 - 我不在乎 班死了
- There's a lot of money at stake here. - I don't care. Ben is dead!
有人死了
We have lost someone.
身为卫合创投代表 我取消探险
As Wexell-Hall's representative, I am calling this expedition off.
- 你无权这么做 - 去看看合约吧
- You don't have the authority. - Check your contract.
我们在丛林里
We're in the middle of the jungle.
你的话要我们听才算
At this point,your authority is what we say it is.
我同意她的看法 我要离开这里
Jack,I'm with her. I gotta get the hell out of here,man.
听我说 班也是我朋友
Look. Ben was my friend,okay?
是我请他来的 没有人心情会比我更恶劣了
I got him into this,and no one feels worse about it than I do.
我并不想做什么蠢事
I don't wanna do anything stupid.
我只想完成我们来此的目的
I just wanna accomplish what we came here for.
我们若放弃 班的死就没意义了
If we turn back now, Ben's death would be for nothing.
我们先去搭船吧
Let's just get back to the boat.
到时再重新组队做决定
We can regroup and make our decision then.
好吧
Fine.
杰克
Jack.
- 也许葛儿是对的 - 她只是害怕
- Maybe Gail's right. - She's just scared.
等搭上船就没事的
Once we get back to the boat, she'll be okay.
等我们搭上船 探险就宣告结束
When we get back to the boat, this expedition is over.
我只送大家去安全的地方
I'm taking these people to safety.
我们说好的
Hey,hey,hey. We had a deal.
把你的钱留着吧 有人死了
Keep your money,doc. Someone is dead.
现在的状况可不妙
We're officially in over our heads.
你说过不会再遇到大蟒蛇的
You said we wouldn't run into another one of them.
可能不会 但我无法保证
And we probably won't, but I can't guarantee it.
所以我会送你们上船
So I'll get you to the boat...
在那之后 我们就毫无瓜葛了
...and after that we're done.
看来答案很明显了
Well,that answers it.
那不代表什么 等我们上船后我会给他更多钱
That answers nothing. I'll just throw more money at him at the boat.
要是他拒绝 我就找他朋友 给一样的钱
If he doesn't take it, I'll offer his friend the same deal.
- 杰克 我们应该要听... - 要是我们现在采不到血兰花
- Jack. Maybe we should listen... - If we don't get to that orchid now...
我们的努力就付诸流水了
...all of our work will have been for nothing.
我需要你的支持 好吗? 这次探险对你我而言都很重要
I need your support,okay? You have as much riding on this as I do.
别让我失望
Don't let me down.
动物星球频道播过 大蟒蛇很凶的
I saw this special on Animal Planet. Anacondas are vicious.
它们猎杀只是好玩
They hunt for sport. Don't even need to see you.
它们用舌头感测猎物的体温
Just use their tongues to sense body heat...
拜托你闭嘴
Shut the hell up.
我朋友的朋友是拍纪录片的
I knew this guy who knew this guy who shot documentaries.
他曾经带一组人去亚马逊河 结果全都被蛇吞了 是真的
He went to the Amazon with this crew, and they were all eaten by snakes.
拜托 那只是谣传
Come on,you knew a guy who knew a guy,that's an urban myth.
班的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about Ben.
我不该继续在曼河上航行的
I never should've stayed on the Mendranang.
这话什么意思?
What do you mean?
我想他不会告诉其他人 但我以为你知道
Well,I figured he didn't tell the others, but I thought you knew.
知道什么?
Knew what?
杰克多付我五万叫我继续开船
Byron offered me an extra 50 grand to stay on the river.
我告诉他情况不妙 但他想冒险一试
I told him it might get rough, but he wanted to risk it.
别怪他
Hey. Don't blame him.
那是我的决定
It was my call.
我接受了他的出价
I took the money.
我以为我可以把大家送到的
I thought I could get us through.
你想怪任何人 就怪我吧
You wanna blame anyone? You blame me.
这双靴子真是害惨我了
These boots are killing me.
- 克尔 - 干嘛?
- Cole. - What?
你的脖子...
You got some....
妈呀 那是什么?快把它弄掉
Oh,God,what is that?! Get it off! Get it off!
- 快弄掉! - 别激动
- Oh,my God! Take it off! - Relax.
- 救命!救命! - 别乱动
- Help me! Help me! - Hold on.
- 救命 帮我弄掉它! - 冷静点
- Get it off me! - Hey! Calm down!
- 帮我弄掉! - 冷静点!
- Get this off me! - Calm down!
克尔 冷静点
Cole! Cole! Calm down.
那是什么?
What is it? What is it?
- 快弄掉啊 - 好了 你看着
- Get it off me. Get it off. - All right. Look.
- 这只是个打火机 - 不行 你不能烧我
- Just a lighter. Just a lighter. - Oh,hell no! You ain't burning me!
好 好 好
Okay. Okay. Okay.
你烧伤我 我就宰了你
You burn me,I'll kill you.
- 好 好 好... - 很好
- Okay,okay,okay. - All right.
- 你还好吧? - 还好
- You all right? You okay? - Yeah. I'm fine.
- 怎么了? - 等等 手举起来
- What? - Hold on. Put your arms up.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
干嘛摸我衣服底下
Why are you going under my shirt?
- 你干嘛?怎么回事? - 老天爷
- What are you doing? - Jesus.
怎样?
What,what? What is it?
有什么?到底是什么?
What is it? What is it?
有人有带火把吗?
Anybody got a blowtorch?
停
Stop!
小心
Careful.
- 什么... - 那玩意若咬到你
- What's it... - If that thing bit you...
你就瘫了
...you would be lumpuh.
像石头一样麻痹两天
Paralyzed,like stone,for two days.
- 这家伙叫什么名字? - "拉巴巴图" 石蜘蛛
- What do you call this fella? - Laba laba batu. Stone spider.
我帮卫合创投找到下一个标的了
I may have discovered a valuable new anesthetic agent for Wexell-Hall.
别管卫合创投了 这可以吸引到更好的金主
Oh,no,no,no. Forget Wexell, we can get this to the highest bidder.
好了 献宝时间结束
All right. Show and tell's over.
我们得赶去搭船了 快穿上鞋 我们走吧
We gotta get to that boat. Put your boots on and let's go.
妈的!
Bugger it.
那是什么玩意?
What the hell was that?
真是要命
Holy bloody hell.
天啊 那是什么?
Whoa! What was that?
我的老天
Oh,my God.
那是什么?
What the hell was that?
快走
Come on.
不 不...不会吧
No,no,no! Oh,come on,man!
发生什么事了?
What the hell happened?!
李文斯顿!
Livingston!
原因在此
Here we go.
他喝醉摔下船了
He got drunk and fell off the bloody boat!
你朋友!现在我们该怎么办?
Your friend! Your friend! Now what we gonna do now?!
妈啦!
Shit!
搜寻残骸
Search the wreckage.
找出任何可用的物资
Find anything we can use.
也希望能找到电话
And hope to God there's a phone.
拜托 拜托
Come on,come on.
有了
Yes.
哈啰?
Hello?
- 拜托 快通啊! - 有回应吗?
- Come on,come on! - Anything?
- 没有 - 继续试
- Nothing. - Keep trying.
你以为我在干嘛?
What do you think I'm doing,Jack?!
妈啦
Hello? Shit.
哈啰?
Hello?
回答啊 哈啰?
Come on,man. Hello?
(信号弹)
继续找!
All right,keep looking!
没有电话?
No phone?
- 没有 - 无线电也没回应
- Nothing. - Couldn't get a signal on the radio.
现在怎么办?
Now what?
怎么了?
What's going on?
这些是哪来的?
Where'd these come from?
- 罗帕族 - 谁?
- Lopaks. - Who?
原住民
Local tribe.
- 猎头族的后裔 - 什么?
- Descended from headhunters. - What?
他们居住在此已数千年
Been in this region for thousands of years.
- 猎头族? - 这附近还有一些村落
- Headhunters? - There's still some villages here.
- 这是他们钓鱼的地方 - 等等
- Must be one of their fishing spots. - Hold on,excuse me.
你说"猎头族"?
Did you say headhunters?
他们已经超过一世纪没猎头了
There haven't been practicing headhunters in Borneo for a century.
没猎并不代表不记得怎么猎
Just because they ain't practicing don't mean they don't remember how.
他们一定住在这个支流的岸边
They must be along this branch of the river.
我们可以去找他们的村落 也许他们能借船给我们
If we can find their village, maybe they can lend us a boat.
给我等一等 去找猎头族 而不是逃命?
So wait a minute. We just gonna walk towards the headhunters,not away?
对
Yeah.
是啊 早死早超生
Yeah,yeah,that makes sense.
我饿到愿意拿我阿嬷换一颗糖果
Oh,God. I'm so hungry,I'd sell my grandmother for a Tic Tac.
你敢再提食物的事
You mention food one more time...
我就投票让你出局
...I'm voting you off this island.
妈呀
Oh,God.
- 那是不是... - 李文斯顿
- Is that... - Livingston.
老天 他出了什么事了?
Oh,my God,man. What the hell happened to him?
大蟒蛇
Anaconda.
若是蛇吞了他
If he was eaten by the snake...
- 为什么又... - 听着 听着 给我听着!
- Why is his body... - Listen,listen!
这些家伙在消化食物时很脆弱
All right. These things are at their weakest when they digest.
但若遭受威胁 它们就会吐出食物 再度攻击
But if threatened,they will spit up their food and attack again.
你是说有条蛇空着肚子到处逛?
What? There's a snake out there with an empty stomach?
- 对 - 是吞了班的同一条吗?
- Yeah. - The same one that got Ben?
不 不是的 不可能是同一条
No. No. There's no way that snake could've gotten to Livingston.
- 一定是另外一条 - 你说过几公里内
- It had to be another one. - You said there wouldn't be...
- 不会有其他蛇的 - 是不会
- ...another one for miles. - There wouldn't.
- 除非... - 除非什么?
- Unless.... - Unless what?
- 除非是交配季节 - 我的妈呀!
- Unless it's mating season. - Oh,my God.
- 交配季节? - 对
- Mating season? - Yeah.
公蛇是有地盘的 但当它们闻到母蛇发情
You see,the males are territorial, but when they smell a female in heat...
它们就会从四面八方聚集过来
...they come running from everywhere.
母蛇会找一个潮湿的泥坑 公蛇会一起找上母蛇
Females find a nice,wet,muddy pit, and they all go after her at once...
形成一个臣大的交配蛇球
...in one big mating ball.
所以那些蟒蛇在开轰趴?
So there's some snake orgy out in the jungle?!
差不多了
Yeah. Something like that.
听着 天快黑了
Look,we're losing the light.
我们得尽快抵达村落 所以请大家注意
All we gotta do is get to that village. So please,pay attention.
别脱队了
Do not stray from the group.
我们走
Let's go.
保持安静 神圣的墓地
Stay quiet. Sacred burial ground.
老天爷
Jesus.
你说过那是你看过最大条的大蟒蛇
I thought you said that anaconda was the biggest you'd ever seen.
刚才还是
It was.
- 但这条... - 更大
- Well,this one's.... - Bigger.
公蛇一定都跑来找母蛇了
The males must've come through here looking for the female.
这太扯了
Some bullshit.
- 他们搭船走了 - 他们走得好
- They took their boats. - Good for them.
对我们可不好了
Bad for us.
哪一条是曼河?
Which one's the Mendranang?
右边那条 左边是托库河
On the right. The Tokut keeps going to the left.
- 那是到新高打最快的路线 - 要多久?
- Fastest way to Kotabaru. - How long?
两天内就能在五星级饭店里泡澡
You'll be soaking in a tub at the Four Seasons in two days.
我们连船都没有
How,man? We don't even have a boat.
我们自己造一艘
We're gonna build one.
这样拆别人房子 不被打死才怪
Man,do that in my neighborhood, and that's your ass.
乱扯!
Shit.
珊
Sam.
你觉得这像什么?
What does this look like to you?
天哪
My God.
不朽之花
Perrinia immortalis.
现在知道那些蛇为何这么大了
Now we know why these snakes are so big.
什么?
What?
森蚺到死之前都还会继续成长
Anacondas keep growing till they die,right?
这些是比尔看过最大的蟒蛇
And these are the biggest Bill's ever seen.
- 因为它们活的比较长 - 没错
- Because they're living longer. - Exactly.
因为不朽之花进入了食物链
Because Perrinia immortalis is part of the food chain.
这些蛇超越了海夫利克极限
These snakes have transcended the Hayflick limit.
花的药性如我们预期的起了作用
The chemical in the orchid does exactly what we predicted.
而这不是理论 是真正的实现
And not in theory,in the real world.
这就是证明 确认了你的研究成果
This is proof,Sam, of your research,carved in stone.
这就是证明?
This is proof?
这最多只算是个趣闻罢了
It's anecdotal evidence at best.
- 我们去采花 查明一切吧 - 你疯了
- Let's get to the orchid and find out. - You are out of your mind.
你知道我们有多接近那些花吗?
Do you have any idea how close we are?
血兰花的发现地在此
The orchid was found here...
在曼河上 靠近下一个湾道
...on the Mendranang, just around the next bend.
- 我们会经过 - 我们不会
- We'll be going right past it. - No,we won't.
我们要走托库河
We are going down the Tokut.
要是我们继续走曼河 要花一周才能到达
If we go down the Mendranang, it's gonna be a week...
下一个村落 我可不想等那么久才洗澡
...before we reach another village. I'm not waiting that long for my bath.
决定权不在你
Yeah,well,it's not up to you.
杰克
Jack.
你可以改天再回来
Maybe you can just come back.
回来?
Come back?
过七年再来?万一花不见了呢?
In seven years? What if it's not here?
万一有人决定开恳整个盆地呢?
What if some local farmer decides to slash and burn the entire basin?
结果稻田取代了不老泉
Instead of the fountain of youth, we'll have a giant rice paddy.
这是我们唯一的机会 你知道的
This is our only chance. You know it is.
我们都到这了 你真的要放弃?
Do you wanna give in when we're this close?
听我说 你知道我支持你
Look. You know I got your back,right?
我们一起面对过无数困难
We've been in the trenches a hundred times together.
- 但我不打算进那个丛林 - 真直接啊
- But I'm not going in that jungle. - Damn straight,man.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
这是我的探险 我们要去采兰花
This is my expedition, and we're going to the orchid.
不要
No.
我们不去
We're not.
别傻了 珊
Don't be an idiot,Sam.
拜托 这比盘尼西林还伟大
This is bigger than penicillin, for God's sake.
这药可以救人命
Lives will be saved by this drug.
人将可以活的更久 更年轻
People will live longer. They'll stay young longer.
要是我们不进行人体实验 就太没人性了
If we don't put this to human trials, it'll be a crime against humanity.
已经死了两个人了
Two people have died already.
科学家本来就是要冒险
Scientists have always risked their lives to change the world.
没有他们冒险 我们就无法... 治愈黄热病 小儿嘛痹 天花
If they didn't,we wouldn't have cures for yellow fever,polio and smallpox.
- 我们都清楚这些危险 - 我们以为我们很清楚
- We all knew the risks. - We thought we did.
直到你开始背着我们做决定
Until you decided to start making decisions behind our backs.
- 你说什么? - 他加价五万叫比尔...
- What are you talking about? - He offered Bill an extra 50 grand...
继续走曼河 而他很清楚曼河很危险
...to keep going,even though he knew it wasn't safe.
我的老天
Oh,my God.
这是真的吗?
Is that true,Jack?
- 我这是为了探险 - 你是为了自己的前途
- I was thinking of the expedition. - You were thinking of your career.
听着 你是我的助理
Look. You're my assistant.
我不需要征询你的意见
I don't need to consult you!
我有权做决定
I'm the one with the authority here.
我们在丛林里
We're in the middle of the jungle,Jack.
在此时 你的话要我们听才算
At this point,your authority is what we say it is.
看来有人不听你指挥了
Guess you got a mutiny on your hands.
谢了
Thank you.
好 抬高
Okay. Keep it high.
小心
Careful.
把它放中间
Center it right here.
好了
All right.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
没看过男人刮胡子吗?
Never seen a man shave before?
可能在你杀短吻鳄之前比较锐利
Probably a lot sharper before you attacked that alligator.
是长吻鳄
Crocodile.
那代表什么意思?
What's that mean?
"新的开始" 是韩文
That means "a new beginning." It's Korean.
我当兵时纹的
I got it when I was in the military.
你怎么会来这里?
What brought you here?
- 说来话长 - 反正我现在也不急着走
- Long story. - Where am I gonna go?
好吧
All right.
事情是这样的 我本来在特种部队服役
Here's the deal. I was in the Special Forces...
我亲眼目赌也做了一些...
...and I saw and did things...
我想忘却的事
...that I wanted to forget.
有时人会为了正义而做错事
Sometimes we do the wrong things for the right reasons,you know?
故事其实并没那么长嘛
It's not very long,as stories go.
是啊
Yeah.
我退役之后 来到这里
Well,I got out of the military...
买下了"血腥玛丽"号
...came here and bought the Bloody Mary.
只是想开始新的人生
Just wanted to start a new life.
谢谢你 杰克
Thank you,Jack.
(李文斯顿私人财产)
数到三
On three.
好了吗?一 二 三
Ready? One,two,three.
成功了
It works.
好耶
All right.
听我解释
Let me explain.
你怎么没把这件事告诉我?
Why in the hell didn't you tell me about this?
只要有人打通电话
The minute someone makes a call...
探险就结束了
...this expedition's over.
没错
Exactly.
我只求多几小时时间
All I'm asking for is a few more hours.
我们先继续沿着曼河过去
We continue on the Mendranang...
采取样本之后再打电话求救
...take our orchid samples, then we call for help.
别想了 我要救大家出去
Forget about it,Jack. I'm getting us out of here.
你要想清楚
Think about this,Gordon.
你就快成为亿万富翁了 你真的想放弃这一切?
You're about to become a billionaire. Do you really want to give all that up?
我不在乎什么钱
I don't care about the money, all right?
我想活命
I wanna live.
它咬了我
It bit me.
你干嘛...
Jack,what are you...
你干嘛?
What are you...
救命
Help.
救救我
Help me.
米契呢?
Where's Mitchell?
他在休息
Resting his feet.
- 要不要我去叫他? - 不
- Should I go get him? - No,no.
- 等一切就绪再去叫他吧 - 好吧
- Let him rest till we get loaded. - Okay.
他脚上的水泡很严重
Those blisters are pretty nasty.
米契
Mitchell...
你还好吧?
...you okay?
米契?
Mitchell?
什么?
What is it?
快说啊
Tell me.
你把他怎么了 杰克?
What did you do to him,Jack?
- 怎么了? - 米契出事了
- What is it? - Something's wrong with Mitchell.
- 什么意思? - 你刚跟他在一起
- What are you talking about? - You were alone with him.
你做了什么?
What did you do?
他在休息 我什么也没做
He was resting his feet. I didn't do anything.
- 糟糕 - 我的老天
- Shit. - Oh,my God.
老天爷
Oh,my God.
葛儿 别叫了
Gail,no! Let's go!
出去!快出去!
Get out! Get out! Go!
快!快啊!
Come on! Come on!
快跑啊!快跑啊!快!
Move! Move! Move! Go!
竹筏!
The raft!
不!你这个混蛋!
No! You son of a bitch!
我们可以再造一艘
We can build another one.
用什么建?
With what?!
With what,Sam?!
我们得搭上竹筏
We gotta get to the raft.
- 才能离开这里 - 拜托 竹筏已经没了
- It's our only way out of here. - FYl,Bill,the raft is gone!
- 我们可以再弄回来 - 怎么弄?
- We can get it back. - How?!
游泳去追吗?
How? We gonna swim after it now?
听我说
Look...
村落在这里
...the village is here.
杰克正沿着曼河过去
Jack is following the Mendranang.
我们穿过丛林
We cut across the jungle.
- 就能在另一边拦截到他 - 没错
- We can catch him on the other side. - Right.
- 在哪里拦? - 他去找血兰花了
- Catch him where? - He's going to that orchid.
只要找到血兰花
We find that flower...
就能找到竹筏
...we find that raft.
感谢天 我是杰克拜伦
Oh,thank God. It's Jack Byron.
听我说 我们出事了
Listen,something terrible has happened.
我们走错河道
We took the wrong way on the Mendranang.
结果遇到瀑布翻覆
We went over a waterfall.
之后我就没见到任何人了
I haven't seen anyone since. I am....
我想我是唯一幸存的人
I think I'm the only one left.
等等 你听
Wait,wait. Listen.
快走!
Oh,shit. Come on!
它在我们前面
It's in front of us.
该死的家伙 它想打散我们
Son of a bitch. It's trying to separate us.
可恶!
Oh,shit.
- 天哪 到处都是 - 关了那玩意
- Oh,Christ,it's everywhere. - Turn that goddamn thing off.
- 它们看得见的 - 没用的
- They can see it. - Doesn't matter.
- 它们能感测我们的体温 - 他说的对
- They can sense our body heat. - He's right.
我们快离开这里
Let's just get the hell out of here.
- 走哪边? - 等等
- Which way? - Hold on.
那边都行
Any way.
- 快走 克尔! - 好啦!好啦!
- Let's go,Cole! - Okay,okay!
- 大家等等我啊 - 快!
- Wait for me! - Come on!
等等我!
Hold on,wait for me!
老天
Oh,my God.
有入口就有出口
If there's a way in,there's a way out.
妈啦!
Oh,shit!
- 你们在哪? - 克尔!
- Guys?! - Cole!
走哪边啦?
Which way?!
这边!
Over here!
- 好 再说一次! - 克尔 往这边!
- All right,say it again! Say it again! - Cole! Over here!
往这边!
Over here,Cole!
- 喂! - 这边 克尔!
- Hello! - This way,Cole!
- 在哪边? - 克尔!
- Guys! - Cole!
老天 拜托!
Oh,my God. Oh,God.
天啊 快亮啊
God,come on!
克尔!
Cole!
不 不 不要!
Oh,no,no!
跟紧一点
Stay together.
好 我保证 能走了吧?
Okay. I promise. Now can we please go?
- 走吧 - 没问题!好 好的
- Let's go. - No problem. Okay,okay.
走哪边?
Which way?
- 我不知道 - 什么?
- I don't know. - What?
什么叫你不知道?
What do you mean, you don't know?
是我跑回来找你的
I found you,didn't l?
阿川?
Tran?
阿川!
Tran!
说话啊!
Say something!
糟糕!救命啊!
Oh,shit! Guys! Guys!
我看得到光线
I can see light.
- 有出口吗? - 我不知道
- ls there a way out? - I don't know.
克尔
Cole!
阿川
Tran!
你们听见吗?
Can you hear me?
克尔
Cole!
你在哪里?
Where are you?
我想我找到出口了
I think I found a way out.
拿着这个 快走
Take this. Go. Now.
- 他们人呢? - 快走
- Where are they? - Go.
我的老天
Oh,my God.
快走
Go.
- 救命! - 克尔?
- Help! - Cole?
- 克尔? - 在这里!
- Cole? - Hey,right here!
就快出去了
Almost there.
真是可恶!
Holy shit!
快点 它在我屁股后面
Move! It's coming up my ass!
救命!我造了什么孽?!
Help me! What did I do?!
克尔在那哪儿?
Where's Cole?
- 克尔 快来! - 克尔 快来!
- Cole,come on! - Cole! Come on!
- 克尔!快!把手给我 - 我卡住了!
- Give me your hand. - Oh,God! I'm stuck!
- 把手给我 - 我卡住了!拉我一把!
- Give me your... - I'm stuck! Pull me!
- 把手给我 - 快点 拜托!
- Give me your arm! - Hurry up! Come on!
天啊!它来了 快拉啊
Oh,my God! It's coming! Let's go! Pull!
拉啊
Pull!
我就知道你行的!珊
That's what I'm talking about,Sam!
真有你的 珊 你超悍的! 你是末代女武士!
Oh,my God! You're the bomb,Sam! You Lorena Bobbitt-ed that ass!
臭蛇 这下你怕了吧?
How you like her now,bitch?!
她又切又剁的把你给砍了
She sliced you,diced you, cut you up!
就算末代武士也没珊厉害
Sam with the samurai action!
你休想!
Hell,no.
克尔...
Cole!
醒醒 快醒醒啊
Get up,Cole. Get up,man. Wake up,man.
快醒来 醒醒啊
Come on,man. Wake up.
不...
No,no,no.
他没呼吸
Cole. He's not breathing!
- 他还有脉搏 - 给他一点空气!
- He's got a pulse. - Give him air!
好的 好的
Okay.
再来!再来!
Again,again!
醒醒!你不准死!
Come on,wake up! Don't you die!
别死啊!不!
Don't die. Come on,no.
搞什么? 放开我!放开我!
What the fuck?! Get it off me!
- 没事了! - 别激动 你没事了
- No,no. It's okay! It's okay! - Hey,it's okay.
是我 躺好别动
It's me. Stay down.
- 我没事了? - 你没事了
- You're okay. - I'm okay?
- 是的 - 你没事了
- Yeah. - You're okay.
不朽之花
Perrinia immortalis.
- 那个混蛋终于拿到他的花了 - 花可以都给他
- Son of a bitch finally got his orchid. - Yeah. He can have them.
我只想要那艘竹筏
All I care about is that raft.
走吧
Let's go.
天哪 感谢上帝
Oh,my God. Thank God.
我知道米契出了什么事了
I think I know what happened to Mitchell.
我不能让你们拿走它
I can't let you take that.
你们看起来真凄惨
You guys look like hell.
- 你根本不知道什么叫凄惨 - 抱歉
- You don't know what hell is. - Oh,I'm sorry.
- 但你们让我别无选择 - 你杀死米契之前
- But you gave me no choice. - Did you give Mitchell one...
- 有让他选择吗? - 我没杀死他
- ...before you killed him? - I didn't kill Mitchell.
你只是
No...
让他等死
...you just let him die.
我看到他手臂上的蜘蛛咬痕
I saw the spider bite on his arm.
我该怎么办?
What was I supposed to do,Sam?
- 做正确的决定? - 只要开始永远不嫌晚
- The right thing? - It's always a good place to start.
你别做傻事了
Let's not be stupid about this.
我们去采花 然后就能回家了
Let's get to the flower, we can all go home.
交配蛇球
The mating ball.
火把给我
Give me the flare.
把他绑起来
Tie him up.
快!
Now!
- 把花装满背包 - 你别开玩笑了
- Fill it up. - You've gotta be kidding me.
我看起来像开玩笑吗?快去装!
Do I look like I'm kidding?! Fill it up!
起来!
Get up!
- 快去采花 - 好
- Now get the flowers. - Okay.
把背包扔给我
Throw me the pack.
把枪放下!
Drop the gun!
把背包扔给我
Throw me the pack.
快起来 比尔 起来
Get up,Bill! Get up!
加油!
Come on,man!
起来啊!
Get up!
起来!
- 珊 快爬啊! - 珊 快爬啊!
- Sam,come on! - Sam! Come on!
- 快爬过来 快点! - 快爬啊 珊
- Come on,girl! Hurry up! - Come on!
- 珊 快点! - 快爬啊 珊
- Sam! Come on! - Come on! Hurry up,Sam!
- 你行的 加油 - 你行的 加油
- Come on,baby! - You got it,honey,come on!
该死!
Shit!
- 加油 快! - 就快到了!
- Come on,baby. - You got it!
- 你行的 加油 - 加油 就快到了!
- You got it,honey! - Almost there! Come on!
- 蜘蛛! - 手伸过来 快点!
- Spider.... - Reach for me!
快点!伸长点!再过来!
Come on,Sam,please! Just reach! Reach!
把手给我
Give me your hand.
- 快点! - 在这里!
- Come on! - Right here,Sam! Right here!
不 不 不要!
No! No! No!
不要!
No!
哦!老天!
Oh,God!
继续爬! 继续爬!加油!
Come on,Sam! Come on!
- 继续爬! - 快!
- Keep coming! - Come on!
继续爬上来! 继续爬!加油!
Climb up that wall,Sam! Keep coming.
继续爬!
Come on,girl!
- 加油! - 继续爬!我抓住你了!
- Come on! - Come on. I got you!
来!快过来!
Come on,Sam,get back!
哦 该死!哦 该死!
Oh,shit! Oh,shit!
喂!
Hey!
在这里 臭家伙
Over here,bitch!
我的老天!
Holy shit.
打得好
Nice shot.
我就说嘛
What can I say?
我可行了
I'm a bad man.
你们两个还蛮登对的
You two look like you made up.
它其实还不坏
He's not so bad.
还好吧?
How's that?
好多了
Much better.
我想我死不了
I think I'll live.
很好
Good.
有你在身边也挺不错的
It's kind of nice having you around.
- 我还要多久才能洗澡? - 到新高打市
- So how much further to my bath? - Kotabaru?
还要...
I'd say...
- 一天 - 一天?
- ...another day downriver. - Another day?
- 我可不想再划一天了 - 好吧
- I'm not rowing another day,homeboy. - All right.
那我们可以走那条捷径...
Let's see,we got this shortcut right up...
不要!
No!